Elementary School
Entrance Ceremony
Okay?
Um...
Yeah...
It's all blurry.
Rin-chan, Kouki, stand next to each other!
Okay!
Kouki-kun!
Say "cheese"!
Next, I'll take a photo of you with Rin-chan, Daikichi-san.
Nah, I don't need a shot of myself.
You have to! She'll grow up before you know it.
So you have to keep a record of everything!
Sure.
Daikichi-san, your expression is stiff...
ashita no koto wa wakannai
We don't know what'll happen tomorrow.
kore tte gisei to wa chigau
This feels different from a sacrifice.
nanika ga chigau
Something feels different.
batsu ge-mu ja nante omowanai
I'm not thinking of it as a punishment game.
de nande na no ka wa wakannai
I still don't know why.
chotto shakuzen to shinai kedo
Even though I don't quite feel satisfied with that,
kimi no sonzai ima daiji da nante mon ja nai
there's no question that you're important to me now.
owaranai koto nante kono yo no doko ni mo nai
There's nothing in this world that's endless.
naku no wa tsurain ja nai no
Isn't it painful having to cry?
ai no Sweet Drops, Sweet Drops
Love's sweet drops, sweet drops.
zutto yume mite itai ne
Don't you want to keep dreaming forever?
motto yasashiku shitai ne
Don't you want to be kinder?
kimi to iraretara Happy
As long as I'm with you, I'm happy.
onna no ko tte tsuyoi ne
Don't you think girls can be strong?
dakedo tokidoki yowai ne
Even though we can be weak sometimes.
bokura no negai wa Happy Happy Happy
Our wish is for happy, happy, happy.
sonna hibi mo Happy
Those days can also be happy.
Just wanna make you happy
Just wanna make you happy.
Again?!
Rin! How many times have I told you not to go wandering off?!
Uh-huh...
You're a big girl now, so shape up!
Don't just say "Uh-huh"!
Daikichi, can we buy this for a snack?
A snack?!
Well, it looked good...
Haven't you ever had cereal before?
No.
Maybe it's too much for me?
No, I don't mind buying it...
But that's the kind of thing you have for breakfast.
It's okay to eat sweets with rice?
Hmm... It does look like a sweet...
But you can have it as a meal.
You put milk on it.
Huh...?
Why don't you have it for breakfast tomorrow?
Yeah! I will.
Are you going to have it too, Daikichi?
Nah. It doesn't fill me up...
Put your cereal in here.
Okay!
Daikichi, you're terrible at that.
I'm losing the oils in my hand...
You're like Grandpa!
Oh, shut up!
Then I'll watch you do it!
Daikichi, there are cherry blossoms over there, so let's go home this way.
Sure.
They're blooming all over the place!
Because it's warm out.
Huge, isn't it?
They're in full bloom.
Since you're just starting elementary school,
what do you say we plant something to commemorate it?
Commemorate?
It's kind of like a remembrance.
Every year, both you and the tree would get bigger.
Huh...
You know, I have my own tree.
At home?
At my parents' house.
When I was born, they planted a fragrant olive tree.
For Kazumi, they planted a tea olive tree.
Are fragrant olive trees the ones that smell good?
That's right.
I don't know the tea olive tree.
Let's see, the tea olive tree has some plain flowers and not much of a smell...
That's why Kazumi used to say, "It's not fair!"
And she'd tear the flowers from my olive tree.
When I told her that I'd trade, she said, "I don't want any hand-me-down!"
Huh? That's a bad memory,
so why am I thinking about doing the same thing?
But if we're going to do it, I think it'd be more fun
to make it a pretty flower or something that blooms, you know?
Or a fruit you can eat...
I wanna do a loquat!
A loquat?
Yeah, a loquat!
I had loquat seeds from before.
You plant the seeds?
I can eat as many loquats as I want!
Only if they actually grow.
Actually, I was thinking of planting a tree that's about as tall as you, Rin.
I can't plant the loquat seeds?
It takes longer for a tree to get big, compared to morning glories and the like...
It's like that expression.
"It takes 3 years for peaches and chestnuts to bear fruit...
Note : Proverb meaning "Your actions often take time to bear fruit."
...and persimmons take eight"!
You really are Grandpa's girl, aren't you?
How long for loquats?
I don't know, but what if it takes 10 years?
I can wait.
By that time, you'll probably be more interested in fancy sweets.
I can't imagine it...
Daikichi, hurry up!
If we don't hurry, it'll be a long time before we can eat them!
Yeah, yeah...
Is this enough?
Yeah. If it's too deep, the bud won't be able to come up.
I see.
You're Grandpa's girl through and through...
I hope the bud comes up soon!
Yep...
Rin, do you know what a ninja is?
Yeah, Kouki-kun says he's gonna be a ninja.
They say that ninjas jump over a hemp plant every day,
so as the plant gets bigger and bigger and by the time it's full grown,
they're jumping at an incredible height.
Huh...
Why don't you try that with your loquat?
I will!
Like that.
Like that?
Uh-huh.
Hey, how high does a loquat tree get?
About as high as our roof?
I don't know... Well...
Yeah, that's probably about right...
Okay, let's go inside.
All right, after ten more times!
I wonder if it'll sprout tomorrow.
Probably not by tomorrow...
Did you remember everything?
Uh-huh.
My teacher said someone from home has to check my schedule, too.
What a pain...
They didn't do this when I was a kid.
You're right. It says, "Please confirm."
Words for Communication
Fun Arithmetic
A fire?
Police car, I believe...
A crime?
I don't know.
Daikichi, attach this whistle to my satchel.
Rin...
If somebody you don't know starts talking to you,
you blow on this to make a loud sound.
Yeah.
And then run to any house!
A store would be fine, too!
All right!
Rin! School!
Daikichi! Come on, get up!
I'm gonna be late!
Okay...
Thank you for the food.
Thank you for the food!
You put milk on it.
Can I eat just a little bit of it like this?
Yeah, I guess.
Pet dogs eat this kind of thing.
That's dog food!
It's only for dogs.
Really?
That's right!
Humans can't eat dog food!
Huh...
Don't look regretful about it!
Is it good?
Uh-huh. Tasty!
Rice balls are still number one, though.
Those rice balls are tough to beat.
Daikichi, your phone!
Yeah...
Good morning!
I'm sorry. Kouki was so enthusiastic, he rushed out!
Oh, that's okay.
No problem.
Right...
Kouki-kun's here!
He's here.
What's up?
Kouki-kun, you've got burrs all over you!
What animal trail did you take to get here?
I'm not an animal!
And what's with your hair?
Rin, go get a comb.
Okay!
Jeez, your satchel is scratched up now...
And I bet you scraped that stick across people's walls too, didn't you?
Are you psychic?!
It's completely obvious to me!
Is it because you did the same thing when you were little, Daikichi?
Rin, hurry up and get ready!
Okay!
What's that look for?
See you later!
Hold on a second!
You still have time...
What's wrong?!
Kouki-kun!
You're not supposed to blow that unless something happens!
Knock it off!
Quit blowing that thing!
Otherwise when you really do need help, nobody's going to come!
Got it?
Then go ahead.
See you later!
Watch out for cars!
Okay!
Kouki-kun!
Let's take this way!
We're not supposed to go out of our way.
This isn't going out of our way. It's a shortcut!
I hear that ninjas...
...always take paths like this!
Sheesh...
It zigzags!
Right?
Kouki-kun!
You're too slow!
That makes the shortcut pointless!
That's not what you do!
Kouki-kun...
That kid's hopeless...
I know, right?
Well, I guess it's...
Really, almost all boys are like that.
Daikichi...
The only ninja training I condone is jumping over the loquat, right?
Right!
Oh, that loquat's a school entrance commemoration, right?
Yeah.
But your olive tree is a remembrance from when you were born,
so it's a little different, right?
Maybe I don't have anything like a fragrant olive tree...
You're a sharp girl...
Did that mom of hers plant a tree or anything?
Or maybe there's one at Grandpa's house.
Yeah, Grandpa might've...
But you don't know anything about one there, do you?
No.
And Grandpa's gone...
If I don't know about it, no one does, right?
I never should've told her about the olive tree...
Daikichi! You've got your elbow on the table again!
Right. Sorry...
Crap...
I didn't think we'd be meeting again.
I had the exact same thought.
This is from her school entrance ceremony.
Thank you...
A tree for Rin?
There is one! There was one!
There is?!
Um... I think there was.
Why are you so unsure about it?
Because Souichi-san is the one who planted it...
Grandpa did...
I'd like to transfer that tree to my place.
What kind of tree is it?
A small one...
No, I mean what type, if you know...
And the location...
Mmm, it's still small,
and the branches are thin...
It's here.
You are a mangaka, yes?
Drawing maps isn't my job!
Which way is north?
North?
The sun rises in the west, so...
The opposite! It rises in the east!
Never mind directions.
Just please draw the street that's in front of the house.
Oh, yeah... Duh.
Well, I've got work to do, so excuse me.
Thank you for the ice cream.
Sorry to bother you when you're so busy.
I wonder if I did have my own tree.
I'm sure Grandpa planted something for you, Rin-chan.
That's what my instinct tells me.
And even if there isn't, I think you could plant another tree
to commemorate you starting elementary school.
A tree that's six years old.
Yeah...
Do you want to see Daikichi's tree?
Yeah, I wanna see it!
It's big, isn't it?
That's because it's 30 years old, just like Daikichi.
It got big, and Daikichi did, too...
It's a fragrant olive, right?
That's right. You know your trees.
Daikichi told me.
This one is Kazumi's tree.
Tea olive?
Right...
Do you remember the big tree in Grandpa's backyard?
Oh, that one?
That's my tree, a tea olive.
Huh...
Huh? This tree...
Grandpa planted it when I was born.
You have the same tree as Kazumi-chan, huh?
That's right.
When I was a child, I always compared my height to it.
I loved it, which is why I continued the tradition here.
Was that a tea olive tree?
Did Daikichi compare his height with his tree, too?
Of course!
Long before the day we first met...
Daikichi, is that...
It has the same leaves!
A six-year-old fragrant olive tree.
Just like mine.
This'll do.
Shoot!
What?
It's too late to jump over this one, isn't it?
I don't think I could even do it...
And we weren't even aware Rin existed until six months ago, you know?
I know.
Daikichi! The train's gonna leave!
Coming!
Well...
I'll see you off.
But...
long before the day we first met,
we were all walking along a similar path.
nichiyou no hareta hirusagari
It's a sunny Sunday, early in the afternoon.
kyou wa doko e yukou?
Where should we go today?
kayoi nareta itsumo no michi ga
This path I've grown so used to taking
mabushiku kagayaite mieru
seems to be shining brightly,
terasu atatakai taiyou to
as long as the warm sun is shining
tonari ni kimi ga ireba
and you are here beside me.
mou High High High
I'm already high, high, high.
hashagidasu kimochi ni
I feel like frolicking about.
utae Life Life Life
Let's sing, life, life, life.
koe wa dokomademo
Our voices can go anywhere.
mou High High High
I'm already high, high, high.
maiagaru kaze ni nori
I'm riding on the rising wind.
utae Life Life Life
Let's sing, life, life, life.
koe mo tobihaneru
Even our voices will be bouncing.
Daikichi!
What's wrong?!
What happened?!
There's a strange old man outside!
Kouki-kun...
No... That man is...
What?!
Where is he?!
Daikichi, he's not...
Enough! Both of you, listen to me!
That's our neighbor, Matsui-san!
Don't call him a "strange old man"!
I'm sorry...
I'm... sor...ry...
It's okay, it's okay.
Apparently, my sudden greeting frightened him.
Sorry about that.
No, he was incredibly rude.
Well, be careful going to school.
See you later!
Thank you.
When you ran away, you dragged Rin along with you.
But Kouki-kun made a mistake...
If Kouki's with you, I feel a little more at ease.
Just a little?!
Yeah, just a little!
You're still a runt!
I'm not a runt!
We're going to be late...
Good afternoon. Rin here.
Do you want to hear a scary story?
The skeleton of the science room walks to the music room at night.
There he plays "who laughs first" with Beethoven.
Reina-chan told me that inside a really dark futon.
After that, she told the adults too.
The next story is "Secretly Running Away From Home"
Episode 7
Secretly Running Away From Home
Daikichi, take me to the bathroom.